so
i'm going to talk through
what i'm writing about and
see if i can kind of work out the flow
of it
you know what i'm basically realizing
in
roughly speaking addressing nihilism
and i take nihilism simply to be
well not so simply but
to summarize i'm taking heidegger as
his word about that essentially the
nihilism
of the current age is not a
not a proclaimed one but unnecessary one
of the age of
technicity that the nihilism
essentially is synonymous with the loss
of the
hearing and understanding
of being or is it would say the
forgetfulness of being
and the thing that's
uncanny says hi to her about this
is the uncanniness is that it doesn't
occur as uncanny
right like it's uh
and that's in a sense why it's not a
proclaimed
nihilism but it's a necessary one that's
given by
our forgetfulness of being
and precisely it's in that we don't
see that we don't see being
the being of beings and therefore don't
relate to
it that is is in essence what
the notion of technicity and the
hyper you could say
utility and instrumentality
we have for beings so in other words
another way of saying that is
we don't notice that we
we basically relate to
the moment and a thing in people and
places
as the condition contingent
as a means for production
for the next contingency
so and really looking at this
if we look at like well okay so so then
in
essentially addressing nihilism
on some level is about being able to
hear being to be able to
well actually not technically not hear
it
but be able to listen
to the world
and our experience in such a way
that beings
reveal the harmony or the glow
of the wholeness of being
right the sense the restoration
the remembering of the sense of
the non-contingency
that sustains and is the source from
which
of sustenance for all beings
and we all know this these moments in
our lives
right
are those moments precisely where
there's an implicit sense that the
current situation
and its shape and its structure glows
with a sense of poorness a sense of
inexhaustible
in that the particulars reveal a kind of
suchness
that glow with this beyond this with
this poorness
in the beauty of the particularity of
the face of the person i'm talking to
and the in the gesture of our
our movements and the way that the
leaves
hang together and
so the part in getting
in touch with that out of the stylism is
the biggest challenge right especially
conceptually to kind of you know
look at what is how does one
if one isn't as a whole aware
and they're unaware that they're not
aware that they don't
experience a sense of wholeness in other
words
it's missing that's missing you know
what
how does one begin to
begin to hear it begin to listen to
that which it's not hearing well it
seems like the first step is to be able
to
awaken to hearing that you don't listen
right and this has to do
with i'm saying essentially is it
primarily is about our relationship with
the logos
and looking at heraclitus right one of
the
one of the fragments right
and if you could say that heraclitus
you know i i think you know following
heidegger and hegel and and
a bunch of philosophers really kind of
see heraclitus is the first
hello maybe not